

hartnagel.david@gmail.com



+971 585968975



Abu Dhabi



11 May 1978



## **Skills**

#### **Teaching**

Master level & B2B courses, Student Mentoring, Remote & onsite teacher

#### Communication

Audience oriented talk, Time management, Reporting

## Soft skills

Active listening, Empathy, Flexibility

#### **Data Science**

Data Strategy, Data Governance, Machine Learning, Deep Learning

## Coding

Python, R, Matlab, SQL, HTML

## Executive

Strategic and Critical thinking, Relationship management

Literature review, Advance Statistics, Experimental design, Publications

## **Human Factors & Ergonomics**

Behavioural analysis, Interviews, Innovative solutions

#### Design

SolidWorks, C4D, 3D printing, MoCap

## Certificates

2023 - Palantir Foundry Data Engineer

**Palantir Technology** 

2023 - Climate Geospatial Analysis on

**Python with Xarray** 

Coursera Project Network

2022 - Data Science Bootcamp

Le Wagon

2021 - Adv. Data Visualization with R John Hopkins University (Coursera)

2019 - Machine Learning

Stanford University (Coursera)

# David Hartnagel, PhD

Data Science Instructor | Research Project Manager | Data Scientist

Married | French Nationality | Emirates ID & Driver Licence

## Summary

Senior Instructor with 15+ years of experience in leading research projects, I completed the competitive Le Wagon bootcamp in December 2022 to deepen my data science competencies. As a freelance teacher I have delivered and managed Data Science and Data Analytics training programs, specializing in tools like Python, Palantir Foundry, and Microsoft Power BI.

I am a team player, always eager to learn and motivated to apply my soft and specialized skills to empower people. Convinced that knowledge is the key to an efficient growth, I will be specially committed to applied projects with real impact.

## **Professional Experience**

## 2023 - present • Data Scientist, Consultant, Teacher & Batch Manager

Freelance: Consultant for pre-seed start-ups | Digital project design, Data management Le Wagon: Teacher and Batch Manager in Data Sciences and Data Analytics | GenAl, NLP, CNN, SQL, Power BI, Palantir Foundry, Group facilitation, Teacher/students management DS bootcamp Final project leader | Leading data scientists, Data project management

CFTE education: Teacher Big Data Analytics, Statistics, SQL, Python, AI/ML, Generative AI

## 2020 - 2022 • Research Project Manager

IRBA: Biomedical Research Institute of the French Forces

Research Project Co-leader | Project management, Experimental design, Statistical analysis Human Factors Expertise Leader | Team management, Data analysis, Reporting

## 2019 - 2022 • Co-Founder & CEO

ColiCycle: a bicycle waste collection project

Company development | Design, Business dev, Manage & Promote (mailing, pitching)

## 2018 - 2020 • Founder & Consultant

PhiléasCog: a website to foster scientific knowledge

HF expertise & Scientific prospection | Data analysis, Modelling, Executive reporting

## 2009 - 2018 • Research Project Manager

IRBA: Biomedical Research Institute of the French Forces

Research Projects Leader | Reply to call for tender, Public procurement, Team coordination, Budget management, Method design, Mechanical design, Test & experiments, Advanced analytics, Statistics, Reporting, International Conferences, Publications, Communication, Teaching, Students Mentoring

Human Factors Expertise Leader | Demand analysis, Action plan, Team management, Interviews, Activity analysis, Recommendations, Reporting

## 2003-2008 • PhD Student and First Position as Researcher

IMASSA: Aerospace Medicine Institute / Health Service of the French Forces

- 2004-2007: "Audio-Visual Fusion and Reference Frames" — PhD Cognitive Science

## Education

2022-2022 • Data Science Bootcamp • Le Wagon

2011-2012 • Master 1 - Ergonomics • CNAM Paris

2003-2007 • PhD Thesis in Cognitive Science • University Paris 8

2002-2003 • Master 2 - Cognitive Processing • University Paris 8

## Interests

**Body** • Basketball, Running, Snowboarding, Kite-Surfing

Soul • Modern Art, Live music, Literature

Senses • Travelling, Sense of wonder, Sustainability

Hands • DIY, Vintage Cars, Sculpture